<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Posts on Miguel Diaz</title><link>https://itscd.xyz/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Miguel Diaz</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 20:54:10 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://itscd.xyz/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dynamic Gelato Tasks</title><link>https://itscd.xyz/posts/dynamic-gelato-tasks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 20:54:10 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://itscd.xyz/posts/dynamic-gelato-tasks/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing around with some smart contract automation through &lt;a href="https://app.gelato.network/">Gelato&lt;/a>. The integration is pretty straightforward,
at &lt;a href="https://zed.run/">ZED&lt;/a> we&amp;rsquo;ve been using it to automate some parts of our system in a reliable and decentralized way. One normal use case for this type of jobs
is to iterate over a queue until you have an item that meets a certain criteria.
You can build a mechanism that works as a FIFO queue very easily with OZ&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code>EnumerableSet&lt;/code>, for example. I want to talk about
a very obvious problem with implementing these type of systems on a blockchain like Ethereum (or EVM-based). These
jobs will be, most of the time, slow. Why? Because of the nature of the exection. Txs, unless
handled in a concurrent way, will be working one by one. Don&amp;rsquo;t expect 10s of txs being executed at the same time.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Simple EIP712 Verifier</title><link>https://itscd.xyz/posts/eip712-verifier/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 May 2022 21:40:46 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://itscd.xyz/posts/eip712-verifier/</guid><description>&lt;p>EIP712 is a great way to validate off-chain signatures in smart contracts with some centralization compromise.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Repo link at the bottom.&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Quoting from the official proposal &lt;a href="https://eips.ethereum.org/EIPS/eip-712">here&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Signing data is a solved problem if all we care about are bytestrings. Unfortunately in the real world we care about complex meaningful messages. Hashing structured data is non-trivial and errors result in loss of the security properties of the system.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>As such, the adage “don’t roll your own crypto” applies. Instead, a peer-reviewed well-tested standard method needs to be used. This EIP aims to be that standard.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>